[{"question":"<p><strong>A play that stimulates the audience to excessive laughter is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["comedy","farce","climax","tragicomedy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A reference to a work of art, person or place whether directly or indirectly is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["allusion","contrast","assonance","allegory"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Literature, a Dramatis Personae refers to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the name of the author","the list of characters in a play","the name of the central character in a play","the voice of the characters in a play"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a writer refers to past events to throw more light on current ones, he is employing<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a retrospection","flashback","historical drama","dramatic shift"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a type of poem?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sonnet","Elegy","Pantomime","Ode"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major narrative technique a novel shares with drama is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["scenes","dialogue","soliloquy","sarcasm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A blank verse<\/p>","options":["is a nonsensical verse","consists of unrhymed five stress lines","is a verse used by the nobility","consists of rhyme in the second and fourth line"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>\"See! how she leans her cheek upon her hand; O! that! wore a glove upon that hand <\/em><\/p>\n<p><em>That I might touch that cheek.\"<\/em><\/p>\n<p>The predominant figure of speech in these lines in&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["conceit","apostrophe","caricature","simile"],"answerIndex":"0","examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The technique used in bringing the plot of a play to an abrupt end is called<\/p>","options":["denouement","climax","endnote","dues ex machina"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>\"Stream of consciousness\" is the name for&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["an Italian rhyme scheme brought into vogue in the sixteenth century","a stage device in which an actor addresses the audience directly","a cultural phenomenon of the eighteenth century"],"answerIndex":"0","examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Which of the following was not written by Chinua Achebe?<\/p>","options":["Girls at war","Anthills of the Salvador","No longer at Ease","Arrow of God"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>\"Even now that the typhoon of your tongue is blowing away the roof of my refuge, leaving me with showers of your kindness\"<\/p>\n<p>The most prominent figure of speech in the above is<\/p>","options":["hyperbole","contrast","metonymy","metaphor"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Rhyme and rhythm are elements of<\/p>","options":["cultural poetry","musical poetry","colonial poetry","pastoral"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A mental picture created with words is referred to as&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["illusion","image","symbol","fiction"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The representation of a thing with something closely associated with it is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["epigram","metonymy","synecdoche","symbolism"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Parallelism involves similarity in&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["structure","syntax","sound","lines"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>An iambic pentameter poem without a rhyme scheme is a&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["free verse","blind verse","blank verse","iambus"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a kind of imagery?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["offertory imagery","tactile imagery","visual imagery","kinesthetic imagery"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a figurative expression in <em><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">An African Thunderstorm<\/span><\/em> by Rubadirt?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["pregnant clouds","plaque of locusts","tattered flags","dangling breasts"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The line <em>\"Your mouth, O katty is a museum with many monuments\"<\/em> is both<\/p>","options":["metaphor and hyperbolic","a synecdoche and a metonymy","metaphoric and epigrammatic","a metaphor and an allusion"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A premiere is&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["a soap opera","the first play by a playwright","a play with social criticism in it","the first performance of a play"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A long narrative in which the fate of a community is dependent on the life and activities of the hero is<\/p>","options":["A tragedy","A legend","An epic","A historical narrative"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Point of view in Literature is related to<\/p>","options":["the narrator","the author","the setting","the hero"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>Setting refers to both<\/p>","options":["time and place","place and space","place and mood","place and culture"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary principles<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The main purpose of a satire is to<\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["heighten the personality of the main character in a story","attack the government","incite the reader to rebellion","ridicule or treat a subject or idea with contempt"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary principles<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A prologue usually occurs at the&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["middle of a poem","end of a novel","beginning of a play","none of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary principles<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>In a literary work, the character whom the hero struggles against is called his<\/p>","options":["alter ego","opposite","mentor","antagonist"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Out, Out, thou strumpet fortune! All ye gods,&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>In general synod, take away her power,<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Break all the spokes and fellies from her wheel<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>And bowl the round knave down the hill of heaven<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>As low as to the friends<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p>In the above lines, the persona is<\/p>","options":["enchanted with fortune","praying to the gods for good fortune","intensely angry with fortune","none of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Out, Out, thou strumpet fortune! All ye gods,&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>In general synod, take away her power,<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Break all the spokes and fellies from her wheel<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>And bowl the round knave down the hill of heaven<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>As low as to the friends<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em>The device adopted in talking of fortune is<\/em><\/p>","options":["pomposity","analogy","axiom","personification"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"}]